hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and in this podcast I
talk about ways for you to grow your
coaching business to reach more clients
and to make more money so that you don't
have to struggle so that you can
actually make six figures working 5 to
15 hours a week now in this episode I
want to talk about content creation I've
been doing some different content
creation things and strategies lately
that I've seen some great results from
uh more traction than I've been getting
in quite frankly
uh years I've been trying to make
content on my social media for a long
time and but I wasn't gaining the kind
of traction that I'm getting now and so
what I want to talk about is organic
content creation and the psychology
behind that one the first things you got
to understand when it comes to creating
content is it's all in the hook this
applies too to Facebook ads and this
applies to advertising but what gets
people's attention is what gets them to
stay with you and so when you can get
somebody's attention the right way you
can then move them to listen and engage
and that produces the results you want
now engagement for engagement sake not
worth anything you want the right
engagement from the right people and
that's the key is you want to identify
who is your target market so knowing
your Niche is important I did a podcast
episode last week all about finding your
Niche and I can walk you through that
process in that episode very simply once
you know who you want to to reach we
have to take a big picture here and look
at why we're making content see a lot of
people separate these two things they
think that okay I'm going to create an
audience and then I'm going to sell
something and everybody who does that
never does either they never make an
audience and they never sell anything
because their mind thinks that that's
the process because that that that that
makes sense but it's not in reality the
way that you want to go about it instead
the best way is figure out what problem
you can solve for somebody find a group
of people that you can help and create a
digital product or service that you can
Market to them and then you create
content that grows an audience of people
that you can sell to so you do these
things all at the same time and I think
that this is one of the key elements of
content creation I think that we have to
understand that we're not going to
separate the the audience building from
the from the marketing and sales side of
things they're all in one piece okay so
understand that your purpose of your
content that you put out there is not to
change people is not to preach at
people it's to build trust and it's to
help them and bring value to them now a
podcast like this it's a little bit more
preachy right so that's that actually is
kind of the format of a podcast like the
one that we have here but when it comes
to other kinds of content uh that's not
what we're looking for what we're
looking for is to create an experience
that really connects with people that
draws them in so that they they want to
spend their time with us so I want you
to think about that people are out there
with problems that you can solve in a
business okay once you find your
Niche how do you get those people to
want to spend time with you well you
figure out what are they interested in
what are they into what desires do they
have and you bait the hook with what
they desire and so that like honey draws
people in to the thing that you're going
to provide value for now the reason why
we provide value in content is to build
trust so we go
attraction trust building once trust is
built we can present a solution and
close a sale and that really is the four
stages of online business you want to
attract the right people at scale think
of a thousand people that you could help
okay then one once you attract those
people to
you you can solve a problem for them by
getting them in front of you and helping
them around a specific area once you do
this this builds trust with them and
then you can present what you have to
sell what a lot of people get wrong in
sales and marketing is that they're
selling the thing that they have to sell
to people that have no trust in them
they're expecting people to to basically
go to like sleep with them on a one
night stand on the first date it's silly
no human being does that especially not
today and so you don't want to treat it
that way where you're looking for people
that are that are just going to buy from
you something you instead you want to
find people that you can help
serve okay once you figure out who those
people are you figure out what are the
problems they have and it's not that
you conjure up some idea
it's that you actually get them to tell
you what problems they need solved okay
and so like one of the biggest problems
that I solve with people is I help them
with lead generation attracting the
right clients and closing business and
making tens of thousands of dollars a
month in their business without spending
a lot of time or effort doing so okay
and so when you create content your goal
is to attract those people to you to
build trust with you and so what we have
to understand is that content creation
when it comes to organic content
it has to be based around something that
has two factors number one it's related
to their deepest desires what are their
fantasies what are those things that
they think about all the time that they
really really want and the second part
is it has to be super normal
stimulus and this part is a little
bit different than the way that most
people think about content creation the
way that most people think about content
creation is I'm going to I'm going to
provide value I'm going to follow a
trend I'm going to do what a lot of
people other people do but they're not
really thinking in terms of supernormal
stimulus okay and so what is the term
supernormal stimulus well supernormal
stimulus is something that exaggerates
the qualities of normal stimulus to
elicit a stronger response it's an
evolutionary concept on how organisms
attract enhanced stimuli
based on whether it be colors based on
um there's a number of different factors
if we can pull up supern normal stimulus
right here um it has to do with things
in both biologically it has to do with
um psychology it has to do with what do
we see that is outside of the
normality of what we normally see on
social media or that we normally see of
people that are doing the things that we
want so you want to think about the
desire that the person has what are they
dreaming about the most and then what is
slightly exaggerated above the normal as
the hook okay so we're going to hook
people in with two things what do they
desire the most you're also going to
breed
anticipation interest
desire and you're going to make them
curious about what you have to share
okay okay so and you do this all in
about 3 to 5
Seconds here's an example of how that
works
okay is that if I post a picture of me
holding my son upside down on social
media that's different than a normal
photo of a father and son that people
would normally see on social media and
so it will grab people's
attention because it is a um
it's an attention redirect it is it is a
it is a outside of the normal that most
people see it's a disruptor it's
disruptive to what people normally think
about okay so here's one of the things
that we have to think about if you're a
coach if you're a mentor if you're
building a business and your goal is
just to fit in just to be like everybody
else to not push the envelope you're not
going to make
money as far as that goes because the
people that are
succeeding are pushing the envelope
getting people's attention with stuff
that's outside of just the simple Norm
as far as that goes okay now I'm not
talking about you needing to dance on
social media or things like that or you
know you don't you don't need to post
yourself naked by the way those are
forms of supern normal stimulus that's
why they get a lot of traction but you
also want the right kind of traction is
the thing okay so you want to figure out
who is the person that you want to reach
what do they desire the most and then
what based around that desire do they
not normally
see that aligns with what they desire
the most okay so you want that
supernormal stimulus to be based around
the desire that they have if my supern
normal stimulus is me with my hat like
this and being silly and stuff like that
but I'm trying to attract business
owners that's not necessarily going to
work okay and so we have to show people
in a way you have to present ourselves
in a way that that fits into what is
similar to what is
normal but it is on the outlier side of
the extremes not super extreme that it's
so
extreme because that what's interesting
is people have actually adapted now to
social media to not pay attention to
extremes for extreme sake but what they
look for is they look for what looks
normal but has just a little bit more of
context to it and it has to be based on
what they want and so when all of these
pieces are together and you have a hook
that's related to drawing people in
something like
this you know I I always wondered how I
could do
it when I started in my business I wish
somebody told me about this and I
wouldn't have to struggle the way that I
did so often so statements like that
breed curiosity and you could go a step
deeper such as like
this when I launched my first campaign
we lost tens of thousands of dollars
before we made
Millions so that points to both an
extreme of a negative and then a
positive where people want to know the
bigger picture and the bigger story okay
so when you're creating content it's
about pulling people into the story
narrative we all have story narratives
that we can come up with and here's one
of the best ways for you because if
you're watching this right now you're
like Jeremiah I just don't have the
creativity to come up with this you
don't have
to I want you to go scroll on your
social media and
see what content gets your
attention what content trigger something
in you that feels
exciting and pay attention to
and write down maybe five posts as you
scroll for about five minutes on
Instagram that might get your attention
different than other things what do they
have in common okay now here's another
way that you can do this you can prime
yourself to be able to notice and train
your particular activating system to see
the trends and patterns that might work
well to reach your client so what I do
to Prime myself is I start to visualize
who my Target customer is I start to
imagine what their desires are I start
to imagine what they want what they're
struggling with and then I start
scrolling the algorithm with them in
mind as if I am my target client not as
myself but as if I'm my target client
and so what this is is this primes your
mind to notice things by putting
yourself into the mind of your target
client okay and so when you can do this
when you can actually put yourself into
the mind of your Target customer to see
things the way that your Target customer
would see them them this allows you the
opportunity to see things from a
different light and a different
perspective that then you can notice
opportunities that you could borrow from
or use as templates or or or even copy
in your own way you don't want to
necessarily knock off or rip off
somebody's content but you might see
somebody else that makes a piece of
content that has a similar hook you
change a few words do a few things like
that and I'll be honest with you
everything on social media these these
days social media has been around long
enough it's all recycled based on
something of some sort and so gone to
the days where we have to be the first
original person to come up with that
idea but it has to be relevant to the
person that we're trying to reach okay
and so when you can do all this and we
connect the dots because here's the
first piece that's what we get the
attention
with then we can connect the dots with
our
message to what builds trust and
eventually lead somebody to follow us
maybe leave a comment with a with a with
a tagline like a word like leave a leave
a comment of leads if you want to learn
my lead generation system right have you
ever seen that well it's great those are
awesome tools that you can use there's
tools now that when people comment you
can actually then send a message with an
offer that they opt into through your
social media and this is something that
I would highly recommend you do
is to be able to do that this is
something that we're starting to do
we're starting to build out offers that
people can start to do that and then we
can reach our Target clients those ways
with various offers that they can opt
into and sign up for through those
different mechanisms okay and you want
to be able to iterate quickly through
those types of things as well okay and
so when you can do this and you can do
it really really
well it allows you to get the attention
of your target client draw them in into
spending a little bit more time with you
maybe 15 minutes with you to to learn
something from you and then they can
take action on something that you can
lead them to to become a customer or
client of yours or you might get them on
your email list after that and then a
week from now or two weeks from now you
nurture that trust with them and then
over time as you build out your body of
work from your content creation to your
email marketing to what you have to sell
you're able to draw people in
build trust with them to the point that
they're ready to buy and so when you're
thinking about your content creation
process this is how everything that I
look at starts as I as I think about
first off who do I want to reach how do
I want to help them what's the biggest
problem that they
have and then I go to work looking at
how are these people being served right
now I also merge it with what are my
experiences what are the things that I
have done that have helped me and then I
bring all of those together to to create
content that gets people's attention
we're starting to do that much better it
also keeps their attention longer and
this is another phase again I could do a
much better job of this myself I'm
getting better at it where you can
actually even tell people like there's
something at the end of the training
this is another thing you might lead a
leave a hook at the beginning of the
training about something at the very end
that you're going to talk about and then
you draw people in to the training based
on something that is at the very end of
it that they're going to be anticipating
and coming into for okay and so when all
of these pieces come together it
creates the kind of
Desire where people will listen to you
they will pay attention to you they will
they will invest their
time because they want something in
return a payoff some kind of a
psychological reward that they're going
to get out of it and so all of your
content needs to reward the person for
paying attention to you and it could be
very subtle it could be just something
that they're not sure they're they're
just curious and they want to know what
is this thing and so then you feed that
Curiosity with people and then once you
do
this the more you show up with them the
more you build that trust the the
algorithm is going to keep showing more
of your content to these people and now
you're cooking with gasoline and that's
when your content starts showing up
again and again and again they start
engaging more they start joining your
email list and this creates a compound
effect that builds your business
effectively okay and so if you are a
coach Mentor trainer you don't need to
struggle trying to get clients you don't
need to struggle to waste time trying to
come up with content ideas if you can
focus in on who do you want to help what
are they struggling with just serve that
and then when you can if you can pull
those people people run a survey to get
them to tell you what they're struggling
with where they
actually they actually verbalize or
write down the things that they want
that they that they need help with and
you can create offers around those
things and then that will attract even
more people to you and this is the
process that we use anytime we do
content creation anytime we make ads as
far as that goes but it has to get
people's attention you can't just sit on
the sidelines and you can't just just be
like well I have so much value people
are just going to find me you don't want
to be a diamond in the rough you want to
shine brightly to people okay so they
can see what it is that you have and
what you have to offer all right listen
if this has helped you stay plugged into
my podcast subscribe to my YouTube
channel and I'd love to also work with
you inside my client growth accelerator
program where we help people just like
you get more clients and scale their
businesses to tens of thousands of
dollars per month all the way up to
millions of dollars a year all right
we'll talk to you soon have a good one
grow your life
[Music]